Pavitha Pichaimani

SUMMARY

Skilled Software engineer with 6+ years of strong experience in **Android** development, designing, developing, and implementing scalable and responsive applications. with a willingness to learn and practice IoT and cloud technologies like DevOps. GOF Design Patterns & OOP Practitioner

SKILLS

Proficient • Java • Android SDK • Python • C++ • Kotlin • Object Oriented Programming • JSON

• SQL • No SQL • MongoDB • DynamoDB • AWS • Kafka • Data Structures and algorithms

Familiar • IoT • Distributed Systems • Cloud Technology • Microservices • BlockChain

WORK EXPERIENCE

Capgemini Apr 2021 - Aug 2022

Software Development Engineer - Android

Bangalore (India)

- Designed and Implemented new product features for Subway online food ordering application using SOLID principles and Android Design Principles.
- Following Test Driven Development practices. Writing unit tests using **Junit 5** and **Mockito** and helping define the overall testing strategy to achieve 100% code coverage.
- Involve in technical analysis, UX discussion, and **API design** discussions. collaborate with quality engineers, iOS and backend teams to ensure **consistency** and **quality** in all phases of app development.
- Working in an Agile programming environment to define stories, do estimations, and plan sprints
- Well-versed in the version control system (Git), multithreading and asynchronous processing, and Networking library (REST API)

TTi Global Feb 2017 - Feb 2020

Android Developer

Chennai (India)

- Worked on Online training and assessment Android applications for the automobile industry such as Suzuki, Renault, and PACCAR. It provides knowledge of products to its sales executives and tracks their performance. Using this app improves their sales executives performance by 89%.
- Implemented Design patterns like Observer, Adapter, Facade, Dependency Injection and more.
- Configured code coverage and code review library using **Jacoco** and **SonarQube** which increases **performance and quality of code** from 65% to 90%.
- Mentoring and coaching newly hired team members related to applications and processes that helped to reduce onboarding time by 54%.

Anand Tech Media Sep 2012 - Dec 2014

Associate Android Developer

Chennai (India)

- Solely designed and developed 5+ end-to-end kids learning apps with intuitive User Interfaces using **animation** which guide young learners on a delightful journey through key skills in math, reading, phonics, writing, and more.
- \bullet Onboarded and supported various and roid applications on to Azure DevOps CI/CD pipeline

EDUCATION

2008 - 2012 Bachelor of engineering in Computer Science at Anna University

(GPA: 8.4/10)

ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

2021 - 2022 Advanced Certification in Software Engineering for Cloud, Blockchain and IoT from **IIT Madras**Designed and Built Smart Farm Water Management **IoT** application in **Python** as a capstone
project and deployed on **AWS** using AWS EC2, Lambda, Kinesis and DynamoDB.

Link to all Projects